const quizQuestions14en = [{
    question:"Which of these material properties does not influence the temperature of the region near the weld pool in an arc welding?",
    answers: ["Specific heat.",
    "Poisson's Coefficient.",
    "Electrical resistivity.",
    "Thermal conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding protective coatings, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["Painting cannot be considered a surface treatment, since there is no modification of material properties, only aesthetics.",
    "In coatings applied by arc welding, the dilution of the weld metal depends on the welding parameters, but does not vary with the type of welding process.",
    "Abrasive wear coatings applied by arc welding may show cracks without compromising the application.",
    "The thicker the spray coating, the greater the bond strength."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Arrange the following metals in order of electrical conductivity, from highest to lowest:",
    answers: ["silver, gold, copper.",
    "silver, tungsten, gold.",
    "silver, copper, aluminium.",
    "silver, aluminium, gold."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which alternative is correct in relation to the MIG/MAG (GMAW) process?",
    answers: ["Initially the GMAW process was used only with inert gas, however, currently, inert or active gases or mixtures of these can be used.",
    "An important feature of the MIG/MAG process is the excellent control of the energy transferred to the workpiece, due to the independent control of the heat source and the addition of filler metal.",
    "It is not applied to aluminium alloys due to the impossibility of using alternating current to clean the oxides.",
    "One of its advantages is that it can be used manually, semi-automatically, automatically and robotically."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["To work in both constant voltage or constant current modes on the same equipment.",
    "Inductance adjustment.",
    "To ensure the self-adjustment of the arc length in case of the use of the static characteristics of the Constant Voltage type.",
    "High no-load voltage of Constant Current type power sources."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["Inductance adjustment.",
    "To offer pulsed current or other metal transfer control modes.",
    "To ensure the self-adjustment of the arc length in case of the use of the static characteristics of the Constant Voltage type.",
    "High no-load voltage of Constant Current type power sources."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["Inductance adjustment.",
    "To ensure the self-adjustment of the arc length in case of the use of the static characteristics of the Constant Voltage type.",
    "Reduced transformer volume without loss of efficiency or maximum rated current value.",
    "High no-load voltage of Constant Current type power sources."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["Inductance adjustment.",
    "To ensure the self-adjustment of the arc length in case of the use of the static characteristics of the Constant Voltage type.",
    "High no-load voltage of Constant Current type power sources.",
    "To have an energy efficiency of around 90%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which thickness range do you consider suitable for laser cutting AISI 316 stainless steel sheets?",
    answers: ["From 2 to 10 mm.",
    "From 2 to 50 mm.",
    "From 7 to 14 mm.",
    "From 15 to 20 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a phenomenon that can occur in brazing/soldering operations:",
    answers: ["Wetting and small melting of the base metal.",
    "Melting of the filler metal and of the flux.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and filler metal wetting.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and its bonding to the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a phenomenon that can occur in brazing/soldering operations:",
    answers: ["Wetting and capillary filling.",
    "Wetting and small melting of the base metal.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and filler metal wetting.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and its bonding to the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a phenomenon that can occur in brazing/soldering operations:",
    answers: ["Wetting and small melting of the base metal.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and filler metal wetting.",
    "Capillary filling by the filler metal and its diffusion to the base metal.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and its bonding to the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a phenomenon that can occur in brazing/soldering operations:",
    answers: ["Wetting and small melting of the base metal.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and filler metal wetting.",
    "Capillary penetration of the flux and its mechanical anchoring to the base metal.",
    "Wetting and mechanical anchoring."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is a problem in the use of polymers when compared to metals?",
    answers: ["They are more sensitive to heating.",
    "Highly affected by galvanic corrosion.",
    "Typically, they have low chemical resistance.",
    "Usually, they have a high thermal conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is a problem in the use of polymers when compared to metals?",
    answers: ["Highly affected by galvanic corrosion.",
    "Their properties vary over time (e.g., polymerization of polymers can take hours and even days).",
    "Typically, they have low chemical resistance.",
    "Usually, they have a high thermal conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is a problem in the use of polymers when compared to metals?",
    answers: ["Highly affected by galvanic corrosion.",
    "Typically, they have low chemical resistance.",
    "Polymers are the most creep-sensitive class of materials.",
    "Usually, they have a high thermal conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding the static output characteristic of arc welding power sources (SCPS):",
    answers: ["The static characteristic of a source expresses the dependence of the voltage output on the current output intensity during rapid changes in welding conditions (transients).",
    "The best type of power source for TIG welding is the Constant Voltage Static Characteristic type.",
    "It is possible for two or more arc welding processes to use power sources with the same SCPS type (e.g., TIG and MIG/MAG processes use power sources with a Constant Voltage SCPS type).",
    "The best type of power source for covered electrode welding is the Constant Current Static Characteristic type."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following heat sources cannot be used for the Direct Energy Deposition (DED) process in additive manufacturing application?",
    answers: ["Oxyfuel gas flame.",
    "Electron beam.",
    "Laser.",
    "Electric arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment of parameters in resistance spot welding, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The application of two or more pulses at the same point aims at welding thicker materials.",
    "Welding aluminium sheets is more difficult mainly due to the surface oxide.",
    "The current application time must be the same as the force application time.",
    "The higher the force on the electrodes, the greater the heating at the contact resistance between the sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment of parameters in resistance spot welding, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["Welding aluminium sheets is more difficult mainly due to the surface oxide.",
    "The force application time must go beyond the current application time.",
    "The current application time must be the same as the force application time.",
    "The higher the force on the electrodes, the greater the heating at the contact resistance between the sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The automation of a process can be done by:",
    answers: ["an open-loop control;",
    "a semi-open loop control;",
    "a semi-closed loop control;",
    "a flexible loop control."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The automation of a process can be done by:",
    answers: ["a semi-open loop control;",
    "a semi-closed loop control;",
    "a closed-loop control;",
    "a flexible loop control."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say, from a practical point of view, that:",
    answers: ["for fusion welding to occur, the base metal must be fused;",
    "for fusion welding to occur, molten metal must be added;",
    "for fusion welding, it is not always necessary to heat the joint region;",
    "there can be welding without melting the base metal, as long as the filler metal is molten."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["Applied for few materials (carbon steel, low alloy, stainless steel and hard surfacing).",
    "The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position.",
    "Wires below 1.6 mm in diameter are not used for SAW, just because this process is indicated for large thicknesses.",
    "The SAW process is not recommended for use in the field, as winds can blow the protection off and generate porosity in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position.",
    "Produces a weld pool with relatively large volume.",
    "Wires below 1.6 mm in diameter are not used for SAW, just because this process is indicated for large thicknesses.",
    "The SAW process is not recommended for use in the field, as winds can blow the protection off and generate porosity in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position.",
    "Wires below 1.6 mm in diameter are not used for SAW, just because this process is indicated for large thicknesses.",
    "The application is limited to positions where the flux is maintained in place (flat position or close to it without applying special techniques).",
    "The SAW process is not recommended for use in the field, as winds can blow the protection off and generate porosity in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position.",
    "Wires below 1.6 mm in diameter are not used for SAW, just because this process is indicated for large thicknesses.",
    "The SAW process is not recommended for use in the field, as winds can blow the protection off and generate porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Suitable for long, continuous, thick welds such as those found on pressure vessels, ships, railcars, etc."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a welding operation that cannot be performed and controlled by a machine:",
    answers: ["Removal of the slag in welding with covered electrodes.",
    "Feeding of the filler metal.",
    "Torch displacement along the joint.",
    "To search for and to follow-up the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes, tick the correct alternative.",
    answers: ["All arc welding processes can be carried out in manual, semi-automatic and automatic versions.",
    "In an automatic system there are three groups of elements: sensors, actuators and controllers.",
    "Process automation can be done in three ways: open-loop control, semi-open-loop control and closed-loop control.",
    "The automation of welding processes reduces manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes, tick the correct alternative.",
    answers: ["All arc welding processes can be carried out in manual, semi-automatic and automatic versions.",
    "Process automation can be done in three ways: open-loop control, semi-open-loop control and closed-loop control.",
    "In the automatic control system, the mechanisms verify their own functioning, taking measurements and introducing corrections, without the need for human interference.",
    "The automation of welding processes reduces manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["By itself, brazing/soldering does not require a chemical or metallurgical reaction between the filler metal and the material of the workpieces to be joined. Only wetting is required.",
    "The brazing/soldering temperature must be higher than the eutectic point of the material of the workpieces to be joined.",
    "In autogenous brazing (without filler metal), the use of a pickling flux is essential.",
    "The difference between brazing and soldering is based on the quality of the brazed/soldered joint: a soldered joint has more imperfections, because this joining method is prone to discontinuity generation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The brazing/soldering temperature must be higher than the eutectic point of the material of the workpieces to be joined.",
    "The filler metal does not eliminate surface contamination, pre-cleaning is required (eg, via a flux).",
    "In autogenous brazing (without filler metal), the use of a pickling flux is essential.",
    "The difference between brazing and soldering is based on the quality of the brazed/soldered joint: a soldered joint has more imperfections, because this joining method is prone to discontinuity generation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The brazing/soldering temperature must be higher than the eutectic point of the material of the workpieces to be joined.",
    "In autogenous brazing (without filler metal), the use of a pickling flux is essential.",
    "The flux protection can be exempted when using a neutral or reducing gaseous shielding atmosphere.",
    "The difference between brazing and soldering is based on the quality of the brazed/soldered joint: a soldered joint has more imperfections, because this joining method is prone to discontinuity generation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Once the joint, to be brazed/soldered, is stripped, its surface does no longer need any protection.",
    "Ceramics do not braze to metals, as there are no ceramic-metal filler materials.",
    "In brazing, the formation of the HAZ (dimension and microstructural modification) is independent of the filler metal to be used, as the heating in this region is always lower than the melting temperature of the base metal.",
    "In brazing, there are always lower thermal stresses generated, regardless of the filler metal to be used, because the amount of heat in this region is always lower than when using fusion union."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A conventional diode allows the passage of current in one direction only. A silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) or thyristor operates slightly differently. How does it work?",
    answers: ["An SCR conducts current in both directions until it is turned on and the current flow is then prevented.",
    "An SCR is non-conductive until turned on and then allows current to flow in both directions.",
    "An SCR is non-conductive until turned on and then allows current to flow in one direction only until the flow of current stops when passing through zero (due to the AC waveform).",
    "An SCR is a unique device which allows only AC current to flow."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the effect of the higher ionization potential of the arc gas on the arc voltage, for a given arc length and current value?",
    answers: ["None.",
    "Increases arc voltage.",
    "Reduces arc voltage.",
    "It can either increase or decrease the arc voltage, depending on the arc length."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using brazing/soldering, the joint has better mechanical strength if:",
    answers: ["it is designed to withstand normal stresses;",
    "it is designed to withstand shear stresses;",
    "the gap between the sheets to be brazed/soldered is (approximately) 1.0 to 1.5 mm, depending on the materials;",
    "a butt joint is used in place of a lap joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using brazing/soldering, the joint has better mechanical strength if:",
    answers: ["it is designed to withstand normal stresses.",
    "the gap between the sheets to be brazed/soldered is (approximately) 1.0 to 1.5 mm, depending on the materials;",
    "the gap between the sheets to be brazed/soldered is (approximately) 0.03 to 0.30 mm, depending on the materials;",
    "a butt joint is used in place of a lap joint."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When using brazing/soldering, the joint has better mechanical strength if:",
    answers: ["it is designed to withstand normal stresses.",
    "the gap between the sheets to be brazed/soldered is (approximately) 1.0 to 1.5 mm, depending on the materials;",
    "a butt joint is used in place of a lap joint.",
    "a lap joint is used in place of a butt joint."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How does a thyristor (SCR) power source have its output signal regulated?",
    answers: ["By changing the timing of the thyristor trigger firing, advancing or delaying it along the half cycle of the alternating current, it is possible to vary the thyristor conduction time.",
    "The voltage applied to the trigger determines the thyristor output current: the higher is voltage, the higher is current.",
    "What determines the output current of a thyristor is its electrical resistance, which, in turn, depends on the level of voltage applied to the trigger gate: the higher is voltage, the lower is electrical resistance.",
    "The thyristor output current depends on its electrical conductivity, controlled by the voltage applied to the trigger."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the following welding processes could the applied pressure be considered an essential parameter?",
    answers: ["Electroslag welding.",
    "Friction welding.",
    "Electrogas welding.",
    "FCAW"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the following welding processes could the applied pressure be considered an essential parameter?",
    answers: ["Electroslag welding.",
    "Electrogas welding.",
    "Magnetic pulse welding.",
    "FCAW"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the following welding processes could the applied pressure be considered an essential parameter?",
    answers: ["Electroslag welding.",
    "Electrogas welding.",
    "FCAW",
    "Diffusion welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the physical effects on which High Frequency (HF) welding is based?",
    answers: ["Piezoelectric effect, which is the ability of some metals to generate heat in response to mechanical pressure.",
    "Peltier effect, which is the generation of heat at the junction of two conductors when subjected to an electrical voltage in a closed circuit.",
    "\"\"\"Skin effect\"\", which is the tendency of high frequency current to concentrate on the outer surface of a conductor.\"",
    "Seebeck effect, which is the generation of a potential difference (electrical voltage) between two conductors when they are subjected to a high frequency magnetic field."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the physical effects on which High Frequency (HF) welding is based?",
    answers: ["Piezoelectric effect, which is the ability of some metals to generate heat in response to mechanical pressure.",
    "Peltier effect: generation of heat at the junction of two conductors when subjected to an electrical voltage.",
    "Joule effect, which is a physical phenomenon in which the passage of electric current through some medium results in its heating.",
    "Seebeck effect, which is the generation of a potential difference (electrical voltage) between two conductors when they are subjected to a high frequency magnetic field."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Typical property(ies) of ceramics is(are):",
    answers: ["high thermal conductivity;",
    "high corrosion and abrasion resistance;",
    "high density;",
    "high electrical conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Typical property(ies) of ceramics is(are):",
    answers: ["low density;",
    "high thermal conductivity;",
    "high density;",
    "high electrical conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Typical property(ies) of ceramics is(are):",
    answers: ["high thermal conductivity;",
    "high density;",
    "the ability to withstand high temperatures with no deformation;",
    "high electrical conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Additive manufacturing is suitable for the following levels of quantity and geometric complexity, respectively:",
    answers: ["low, low;",
    "high, high;",
    "low, high;",
    "high, low."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG welding process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "a spray-like metal transfer in all welding positions.",
    "possibility of welding thinner plates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG welding process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "possibility of welding thinner plates;",
    "possibility of welding in windy conditions."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following properties of a gas should be taken into account when selecting a plasma gas for PAW?",
    answers: ["Boiling point (°C).",
    "Ionization potential.",
    "Density.",
    "The ability to react with tungsten to increase the thermionic emission from the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the generation and transfer of heat in the arc:",
    answers: ["Positive electrode polarity is used in processes with consumable electrodes to increase their melting rate, as the anodic region generates more heat than the cathodic region.",
    "The higher the arc voltage, for the same current, the higher its thermal efficiency of the arc.",
    "The thermal efficiency of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is higher than that of MIG/MAG welding with the short-circuit transfer.",
    "The TIG process has low thermal efficiency, as part of the electrical power is dissipated by the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following correctly describes what is happening during the aluminothermic welding process (Thermite Welding)?",
    answers: ["During aluminothermic welding, heat is generated as a result of a chemical reaction between a metal oxide and aluminium powder.",
    "After the aluminothermic reaction ends, a superheated molten metal is poured into the joint to be welded.",
    "During aluminothermic welding, steel and aluminium oxide are melted using an oxy-acetylene welding torch in a crucible built around the joint to be welded.",
    "After the application of aluminothermic welding, a post-heat treatment of up to 600 °C may be required."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following correctly describes what is happening during the aluminothermic welding process (Thermite Welding)?",
    answers: ["During aluminothermic welding, heat is generated as a result of a chemical reaction between aluminium oxide and a metal powder (the metal must be compatible with the base metal).",
    "After the aluminothermic reaction begins, a superheated molten metal is poured into the joint to be welded.",
    "During aluminothermic welding, steel and aluminium oxide are melted using an oxy-acetylene welding torch in a crucible built around the joint to be welded.",
    "After the application of aluminothermic welding, a post-heat treatment of up to 600 °C may be required."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following correctly describes what is happening during the aluminothermic welding process (Thermite Welding)?",
    answers: ["During aluminothermic welding, heat is generated as a result of a chemical reaction between aluminium oxide and a metal powder (the metal must be compatible with the base metal).",
    "After the aluminothermic reaction ends, a superheated molten metal is poured into the joint to be welded.",
    "During aluminothermic welding, steel and aluminium oxide are melted using an oxy-acetylene welding torch in a crucible built around the joint to be welded.",
    "During aluminothermic welding of a large cross-section joint, preheating of up to 600 °C may be required."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of welding processes into “fusion” and “solid-state” welding, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["To have a joint, it is always necessary to apply the heat, except for the Solid-State Welding processes.",
    "Pressure is exerted in processes classified as “Solid-State Welding” in order to increase the area of contact between the surfaces and to achieve better coalescence of the materials to be joined.",
    "\"The pressure, consequently the friction, is the driving force to generate the heat to carry out the welding of the processes classified as \"\"Solid-State Welding\"\".\"",
    "All welding processes classified as “Fusion Welding” use the arc as the heat source."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of welding processes into “fusion” and “solid-state” welding, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["To have a joint, it is always necessary to apply the heat, except for the Solid-State Welding processes.",
    "\"The pressure, consequently the friction, is the driving force to generate the heat to carry out the welding of the processes classified as \"\"Solid-State Welding\"\".\"",
    "In fusion welding processes, pressure does not need to be applied to the parts to be welded, but in some processes classified as “Solid-State Welding” the melting of the base metal takes place.",
    "All welding processes classified as “Fusion Welding” use the arc as the heat source."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of helium compared to argon when used as a shielding gas for TIG welding?",
    answers: ["The arc ignition process is easier.",
    "The fluidity of the weld pool metal is increased and degassing is more effective.",
    "Gas flow rate may be lower.",
    "The arc is cooler (thus the heat-affected zone is reduced)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of helium compared to argon when used as a shielding gas for TIG welding?",
    answers: ["The arc ignition process is easier.",
    "Gas flow rate may be lower.",
    "The heat input is higher, allowing higher welding speeds.",
    "The arc is cooler (thus the heat-affected zone is reduced)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the main characteristics of acetylene is:",
    answers: ["Flame reducing effect on the weld pool metal.",
    "It must be stored in high strength brass cylinders.",
    "It generates the lowest flame temperature among other combustible gases (butane, propane, methane).",
    "Toxic, colourless and with a weak odour."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the main characteristics of acetylene is:",
    answers: ["Flame oxidizing effect on the weld pool metal.",
    "Acetylene is stored in steel cylinders, with a porous substance inside them and there is also acetone.",
    "It generates the lowest flame temperature among other combustible gases (butane, propane, methane).",
    "Toxic, colourless and with a weak odour."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the main characteristics of acetylene is:",
    answers: ["Flame oxidizing effect on the weld pool metal.",
    "It must be stored in high strength brass cylinders.",
    "It generates the highest flame temperature among other combustible gases (butane, propane, methane).",
    "Toxic, colourless and with a weak odour."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the main characteristics of acetylene is:",
    answers: ["Flame oxidizing effect on the weld pool metal.",
    "It must be stored in high strength brass cylinders.",
    "It generates the lowest flame temperature among other combustible gases (butane, propane, methane).",
    "Non-toxic, colourless and odourless."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding thermal cutting mechanisms?",
    answers: ["One of the requirements, for the oxyfuel cutting of the metal to be viable, is that the generated oxides have a lower melting temperature than the metal itself.",
    "The metal oxidation phenomenon is necessary to achieve the cutting action in the carbon arc cutting process.",
    "Plasma cutting is performed with transferred and non-transferred arc. For metals only transferred arc is applicable.",
    "The laser cutting is applicable for ferrous materials only."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding thermal cutting mechanisms?",
    answers: ["Plasma cutting is performed with transferred and non-transferred arc. For metals only transferred arc is applicable.",
    "The metal oxidation phenomenon is necessary to achieve the cutting action in the carbon arc cutting process.",
    "The laser cutting is applicable for ferrous materials only.",
    "The laser cutting is applicable for ferrous and non-ferrous materials."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding thermal cutting mechanisms?",
    answers: ["One of the requirements for the oxyfuel cutting of the metal to be viable is that the metal ignition temperature is lower than the melting temperature of the metal itself.",
    "The metal oxidation phenomenon is necessary to achieve the cutting action in the carbon arc cutting process.",
    "Plasma cutting is performed with transferred and non-transferred arc. For metals only transferred arc is applicable.",
    "The laser cutting is applicable for ferrous materials only."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the technological advantages of Pulsed MIG welding?",
    answers: ["Controlled metal transfer producing almost no spatter.",
    "Prevention of porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Higher welding speeds are possible.",
    "High deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the technological advantages of Pulsed MIG welding?",
    answers: ["Prevention of porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Higher welding speeds are possible.",
    "Suitable for welding in vertical, horizontal and overhead positions, even with spray transfer.",
    "High deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the technological advantages of Pulsed MIG welding?",
    answers: ["Prevention of porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Higher welding speeds are possible.",
    "High deposition rate.",
    "Low average current without loss of high stability of the welding process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "},
    {
    question:"Hardness measurements performed in the HAZ of a steel indicated values above the acceptable level in specimens welded according to a given procedure. Select the procedure change that can be used to reduce the hardness value:",
    answers: ["Use consumables capable of providing a lower amount of diffusible hydrogen.",
    "To use a lower welding current.",
    "To use a higher welding travel.",
    "To use a higher preheat temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hardness measurements performed in the HAZ of a steel indicated values above the acceptable level in specimens welded according to a given procedure. Select the procedure change that can be used to reduce the hardness value:",
    answers: ["Use consumables capable of providing a lower amount of diffusible hydrogen.",
    "To use a higher welding current.",
    "To use a higher welding travel.",
    "To use a higher postheat temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A gouging type of wear that washes away or grooves out the metal surface is called:",
    answers: ["corrosion;",
    "oxidation;",
    "erosion;",
    "abrasion."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The type of wear that pits, perforates, and eventually dissolves metal is called:",
    answers: ["corrosion;",
    "oxidation;",
    "erosion;",
    "abrasion."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Chains and nails are made of:",
    answers: ["high carbon steel;",
    "very high carbon steel;",
    "low carbon steel;",
    "medium carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In a carbon steel welded joint, a zone of reduced mechanical strength is considered:",
    answers: ["the side edge of the weld;",
    "the region located at the top of the weld, as it is made of a metal overheated during welding;",
    "the region of the bead consisting exclusively of deposited filler metal;",
    "the base metal region adjacent to the weld with mechanical properties deteriorated by the welding thermal cycle."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The composition of nodular cast iron closely resembles:",
    answers: ["white cast iron;",
    "grey cast iron;",
    "malleable cast iron;",
    "high carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the main factors that influence the position of TTT curves?",
    answers: ["These are all the chemical elements added to the alloy.",
    "Temperature, grain size and cooling medium.",
    "Chemical composition, grain size of austenite and homogeneity of austenite.",
    "Heating medium, temperature and homogeneity of austenite."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hot welding of cast iron uses which welding process?",
    answers: ["OAW (311)",
    "GTAW (TIG).",
    "SAW",
    "GMAW (MIG/MAG)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hot welding of cast iron uses which welding process?",
    answers: ["SAW",
    "GTAW (TIG).",
    "SMAW (MMA).",
    "GMAW (MIG/MAG)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cold welding of cast iron uses the welding process:",
    answers: ["SAW",
    "GTAW (TIG).",
    "SMAW (MMA).",
    "GMAW (MIG/MAG)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat from the Blast furnace changes limestone into:",
    answers: ["calcium oxide and carbon monoxide;",
    "calcium oxide and oxygen;",
    "calcium oxide and carbon dioxide;",
    "calcium dioxide and monoxide."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element is taken from weld boundaries when carbide precipitation occurs during arc welding of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Carbon.",
    "Chromium.",
    "Nickel.",
    "Molybdenum."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The reason a multi-pass welded joint is typically more tenacious than a single-pass weld is because:",
    answers: ["beads with a smaller cross section have smaller grains;",
    "some martensite is formed;",
    "heating caused by the next pass increases the grain size of the previous pass;",
    "a multi-pass weld has fewer defects (they are remelted by the later passes)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The reason a multi-pass welded joint is typically more tenacious than a single-pass weld is because:",
    answers: ["some martensite is formed;",
    "subsequent beads cause reheating and partial melting of the previous pass, favouring a refinement of a part of the primary solidification structure;",
    "heating caused by the next pass increases the grain size of the previous pass;",
    "a multi-pass weld has fewer defects (they are remelted by the later passes)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardenability of a steel workpiece depends on:",
    answers: ["the initial microstructure;",
    "the workpiece size;",
    "the chemical composition;",
    "the cooling rate."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The chemical elements C, Mn and Nb have specific functions in controlled lamination. Carbon and niobium act as atoms in solid solution or as NbC-forming. What would be the role of Mn in these steels?",
    answers: ["Form a substitutional solid solution.",
    "Act as a self-interstitial atom.",
    "Act as a precipitate former.",
    "Form an interstitial solid solution."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Observing the service temperature, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["at cryogenic temperatures, common carbon steels should be used, as they are more ductile;",
    "the equipment must operate at a temperature lower than its ductile/brittle transition temperature;",
    "in general, mechanical strength decreases and ductility increases with reduction in temperature;",
    "at cryogenic temperatures, Ni-alloyed steels should be used, as they are more tenacious at low temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding surface treatments, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["Surface treatment is any change made to the surface of the material, such as applying a coating, modifying the texture or heat surface treatments;",
    "Painting is not a surface treatment, since there is no modification of material properties, only aesthetics;",
    "The SMAW/MMA welding is not recommended for Weld Overlay (deposition of filler metal upon a substrate), as it does not ensure the dimensional accuracy of the deposited layer;",
    "Abrasive wear coatings, which exhibit such imperfections as cracks, can compromise application."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding surface treatments, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["Galvanizing consists of covering the steel surface with a layer of zinc;",
    "Painting is not a surface treatment, since there is no modification of material properties, only aesthetics;",
    "The SMAW/MMA welding is not recommended for Weld Overlay (deposition of filler metal upon a substrate), as it does not ensure the dimensional accuracy of the deposited layer;",
    "Abrasive wear coatings, which exhibit such imperfections as cracks, can compromise application."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding surface treatments, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["Welding is an important form of deposition of metallic material and is widely used to modify the surface properties of a material.",
    "Painting is not a surface treatment, since there is no modification of material properties, only aesthetics;",
    "The SMAW/MMA welding is not recommended for Weld Overlay (deposition of filler metal upon a substrate), as it does not ensure the dimensional accuracy of the deposited layer;",
    "Abrasive wear coatings, which exhibit such imperfections as cracks, can compromise application."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding techniques for welding cast iron, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["in the cold welding technique, nickel-based or aluminium-based electrodes are used;",
    "a great advantage of using the cold welding technique is that there is no need to use buttering;",
    "a great advantage of using a hot welding technique is that the filler metal can be of cast iron as well, keeping the same properties (such as vibration absorber) and even the colouring;",
    "in the cold technique, the preheating rate is not important, unlike the cooling, which must be done slowly to avoid temperature gradients in the workpiece itself."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"For welding of heat treatable aluminium alloys filler materials with silicon and manganese is often used. Why?",
    answers: ["To stabilize the arc.",
    "To avoid cold laps.",
    "To avoid hot cracks.",
    "To improve the strength of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of defect can typically occur due to the use of a cellulosic-type covered electrode in welding low-alloy steels?",
    answers: ["Hot cracking in the weld metal.",
    "Cold cracking in the heat affected zone.",
    "Porosity formation.",
    "Lack of penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About cold deformation it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Cold working increases hardness and tensile strength and reduces elongation as the grains weld together, making relative movement between them difficult.",
    "Recovery is the restoration of the properties of the cold-worked material that occurs along with the replacement of the cold-worked structure with a new group of deformation-free grains;",
    "\"Between two samples of the same material cold deformed at 20% and 40%, the \"\"40%\"\" one will have a larger grain size;\"",
    "A material subjected to cold deformation hardens permanently."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"During the primary extraction process to produce aluminium:",
    answers: ["aluminium is extracted from aluminium oxide using carbon as a reducing agent;",
    "pure alumina (hydrated aluminium oxide) is produced from bauxite using the Bayer process;",
    "hematite is the most important raw material;",
    "cryolite (Na3AlF6) is the most important raw material."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"During the primary extraction process to produce aluminium:",
    answers: ["aluminium is extracted from aluminium oxide using carbon as a reducing agent;",
    "aluminium oxide is dissolved in molten flux and decomposed into Al and O using electrolysis;",
    "hematite is the most important raw material;",
    "cryolite (Na3AlF6) is the most important raw material."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Iron has the special property of existing in different crystallographic forms in the solid state. In what temperature range does it exist as a face centred cubic (FCC) arrangement?",
    answers: ["Between 910°C and 1390°C.",
    "Below 900°C.",
    "Above 1400°C.",
    "Between 723°C and 900°C."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To which non-ferrous metal is possible to weld steel by fusion welding? ",
    answers: ["To Ni and Ni alloys.",
    "To Ti alloys.",
    "To all non-ferrous metals with buffer layer applied.",
    "To non-ferrous metal with melting temperature close to that of Fe."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Stress Corrosion Cracking (SCC) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The susceptibility to SCC of different metals (carbon steels, stainless steels, aluminium, ...) is more or less the same; ",
    "In the case of SCC, crack propagation is caused by mostly cyclic stresses.",
    "The chloride and oxygen content in the corrosive environment decreases the susceptibility of metals to SCC.",
    "SCC can occur in cases where there is no applied stress, for example, when residual stresses exist from cold working and welding in the metal;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Stress Corrosion Cracking (SCC) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The susceptibility to SCC of different metals (carbon steels, stainless steels, aluminium, ...) is more or less the same; ",
    "In the case of SCC, crack propagation is caused by mostly cyclic stresses.",
    "The chloride and oxygen content in the corrosive environment decreases the susceptibility of metals to SCC.",
    "The SCC is caused by the simultaneous presence of tensile stress and a corrosive environment."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Stress Corrosion Cracking (SCC) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The susceptibility to SCC of different metals (carbon steels, stainless steels, aluminium, ...) is more or less the same; ",
    "In the case of SCC, crack propagation is caused by mostly cyclic stresses.",
    "The chloride and oxygen content in the corrosive environment decreases the susceptibility of metals to SCC.",
    "The chloride and oxygen content in the corrosive environment increases the susceptibility of metals to SCC. "],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which alloys have good resistance to hydrochloric and sulphuric acids?",
    answers: ["Hastelloy alloys.",
    "Inconel alloys.",
    "Incoloy alloys.",
    "Nichrome alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following steels normally tends to soften in the heat affected zone after welding?",
    answers: ["TMCP steels.",
    "Normalized steels.",
    "Ferritic stainless steels.",
    "Austenitic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nitriding is good protection against:",
    answers: ["high temperature wear;",
    "stress-corrosion wear;",
    "abrasion wear;",
    "oxidative wear."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nitriding is good protection against:",
    answers: ["high temperature wear;",
    "stress-corrosion wear;",
    "erosion wear;",
    "oxidative wear."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nitriding is good protection against:",
    answers: ["high temperature wear;",
    "stress-corrosion wear;",
    "adhesion wear;",
    "oxidative wear."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is correct when considering cast irons and steels? ",
    answers: ["Carbon exists in the form of Fe3C in grey cast irons.",
    "Lamellar graphite exists in malleable cast irons.",
    "Cast irons and steels must be welded with higher heat inputs to increase the dilution and thus reduce the carbon content in the weld metal.",
    "There are different types of graphite in cast irons."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is correct when considering cast irons and steels? ",
    answers: ["Carbon exists in the form of Fe3C in grey cast irons.",
    "Lamellar graphite exists in malleable cast irons.",
    "Cast irons and steels must be welded with higher heat inputs to increase the dilution and thus reduce the carbon content in the weld metal.",
    "The preheat temperature is determined by the carbon equivalent of base material and/or the thickness of the workpiece."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is correct when considering cast irons and steels? ",
    answers: ["Carbon exists in the form of Fe3C in grey cast irons.",
    "Lamellar graphite exists in malleable cast irons.",
    "Cast irons and steels must be welded with higher heat inputs to increase the dilution and thus reduce the carbon content in the weld metal.",
    "Cast irons have higher levels of impurities than steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is correct when considering cast irons and steels? ",
    answers: ["Carbon exists in the form of Fe3C in grey cast irons.",
    "Lamellar graphite exists in malleable cast irons.",
    "Cast irons and steels must be welded with higher heat inputs to increase the dilution and thus reduce the carbon content in the weld metal.",
    "Cast irons have higher levels of silicon (Si) than steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In which region of the welded joint cannot hot cracks appear?",
    answers: ["In the partially austenitised area of the HAZ.",
    "In the weld of the joint.",
    "At the fusion interface (line).",
    "In the overheated area of the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Crystallographic arrangement of nickel has:",
    answers: ["BCC structure;",
    "FCC structure;",
    "hexagonal structure;",
    "tetragonal structure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An annealed steel with 0.2% carbon content has microstructure composed of:",
    answers: ["pearlite + austenite (pearlite/austenite ratio depends on the thickness of the component);",
    "ferrite + austenite (ferrite/austenite ratio depends on the thickness of the component);",
    "ferrite and pearlite;",
    "partially bainitic phase."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When HSLA steel is used instead of S235, the section of the material can be reduced because:",
    answers: ["the yield strength is higher;",
    "smaller section means less construction weight, which, in turn, justifies a smaller section of the components;",
    "HSLA-type steels have high resistance to corrosion, so possible section losses are reduced;",
    "the mechanical characteristics of HSLA-type steels are more stable (without considerable fluctuations)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When HSLA steel is used instead of S235, the section of the material can be reduced because:",
    answers: ["the allowable stress is higher;",
    "smaller section means less construction weight, which, in turn, justifies a smaller section of the components;",
    "HSLA-type steels have high resistance to corrosion, so possible section losses are reduced;",
    "the mechanical characteristics of HSLA-type steels are more stable (without considerable fluctuations)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is a rimming steel?",
    answers: ["A steel very suitable for welding",
    "A high quality steel with refined grains.",
    "A cast steel.",
    "A steel without or with very little amount of Silicon."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The most probable metallurgical imperfection in the low-alloy Cr-Mo steels welding is:",
    answers: ["hot crack;",
    "hydrogen induced crack;",
    "lamellar tearing;",
    "lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When using nitrogen as shielding gas in TIG welding (GTAW) copper, one should know that:",
    answers: ["nitrogen increases corrosion resistance and is a strong austenite stabilizer;",
    "nitrogen reduces heat input;",
    "the efficiency of heat transfer for nitrogen is lower than for either argon or helium;",
    "nitrogen will contaminate the tungsten electrode because it is not an inert gas."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When using nitrogen as shielding gas in TIG welding (GTAW) copper, one should know that:",
    answers: ["nitrogen increases corrosion resistance and is a strong austenite stabilizer;",
    "nitrogen reduces heat input;",
    "the efficiency of heat transfer for nitrogen is lower than for either argon or helium;",
    "nitrogen will reduce arc stability."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When using nitrogen as shielding gas in TIG welding (GTAW) copper, one should know that:",
    answers: ["nitrogen increases corrosion resistance and is a strong austenite stabilizer;",
    "nitrogen reduces heat input;",
    "the efficiency of heat transfer for nitrogen is lower than for either argon or helium;",
    "the efficiency of heat transfer for nitrogen is higher than for either argon or helium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with respect to corrosion:",
    answers: ["The passivation phenomenon can be defined as the reduction of the corrosion rate of a metal due to the formation of a film on the metal surface, with protective characteristics;",
    "Many corrosive media, such as acetic acid, alkaline solutions such as sodium carbonate or even drinking water, cause intergranular corrosion at room temperature;",
    "Buttering is a process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "The intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels occurs in presence of corrosive medium and tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with respect to corrosion:",
    answers: ["The use of dissimilar metals with very different electrochemical potentials should be avoided: galvanic cells;",
    "Many corrosive media, such as acetic acid, alkaline solutions such as sodium carbonate or even drinking water, cause intergranular corrosion at room temperature;",
    "Buttering is a process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "The intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels occurs in presence of corrosive medium and tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with respect to corrosion:",
    answers: ["Should be avoided a high ratio between the cathodic and anodic areas in order to obtain a lower and more uniform wear in the anodic area.",
    "Many corrosive media, such as acetic acid, alkaline solutions such as sodium carbonate or even drinking water, cause intergranular corrosion at room temperature;",
    "Buttering is a process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "The intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels occurs in presence of corrosive medium and tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with respect to corrosion:",
    answers: ["To avoid intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels, it is necessary to use base and addition metal with a low carbon content (<0.03%);",
    "Many corrosive media, such as acetic acid, alkaline solutions such as sodium carbonate or even drinking water, cause intergranular corrosion at room temperature;",
    "Buttering is a process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "The intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels occurs in presence of corrosive medium and tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with respect to corrosion:",
    answers: ["To avoid intergranular corrosion in ferritic stainless steels, it is recommended to perform the heat treatment of the welded joint;",
    "Many corrosive media, such as acetic acid, alkaline solutions such as sodium carbonate or even drinking water, cause intergranular corrosion at room temperature;",
    "Buttering is a process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "The intergranular corrosion in austenitic stainless steels occurs in presence of corrosive medium and tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which stainless steel is noted for its ability to provide good resistance to chloride stress corrosion cracking?",
    answers: ["Austenitic stainless steel.",
    "Ferritic stainless steel.",
    "Martensitic stainless steel.",
    "Duplex stainless steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Oxy-acetylene edge preparation chromium nickel cladding can produce which problem for subsequent welding?",
    answers: ["Weld metal embrittlement.",
    "HAZ metal coarse grain microstructure.",
    "Carbide precipitation in welded joint metal.",
    "Higher dilution."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"The probability of brittle fracture of structural steel components is increased by:",
    answers: ["slower loading;",
    "higher service temperature; ",
    "greater thickness;",
    "smaller grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The probability of brittle fracture of structural steel components is increased by:",
    answers: ["slower loading;",
    "higher service temperature; ",
    "lower service temperature; ",
    "smaller grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The probability of brittle fracture of structural steel components is increased by:",
    answers: ["higher service temperature; ",
    "slower loading;",
    "higher load rate;",
    "smaller grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The probability of brittle fracture of structural steel components is increased by:",
    answers: ["slower loading;",
    "higher service temperature; ",
    "presence of defects, especially those of planar type, their size and orientation;",
    "smaller grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the welded joints in a cylindrical pressure vessel is less stressed in service?",
    answers: ["Longitudinal",
    "Circumferential.",
    "Longitudinal and circumferential (all welded joints are equally stressed).",
    "Circumferential, but only if the wall thickness is large."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the welded joints in a cylindrical pressure vessel is more stressed in service?",
    answers: ["Longitudinal.",
    "Circumferential.",
    "Longitudinal and circumferential (all welded joints are equally stressed).",
    "Circumferential, but only if the wall thickness is large."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The permissible stresses in a weld with an incomplete joint penetration welded on both sides can be calculated on the basis of:",
    answers: ["the thickness of the thinner base metal;",
    "the thinner base metal thickness minus the value of the lack of penetration;",
    "the thickness represented by ¾ of the thinner base metal thickness;",
    "the thickness of the weld metal, including the reinforcements of the finishing passes on both sides."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the externally applied stresses in welded joints, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Shear stresses in the transverse direction of the fillet weld are rarely considered when designing steel structures;",
    "The axial stress (in the longitudinal direction) of the weld is of most importance in the design;",
    "When designing butt welds, shear stresses perpendicular to the weld axis are considered.",
    "When designing butt welds (determination of allowable stresses), face and root bead reinforcements are considered as long as they are within the limits prescribed by a standard."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the externally applied stresses in welded joints, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Shear stresses in the longitudinal direction of the weld are important when designing fillet welds;",
    "The axial stress (in the longitudinal direction) of the weld is of most importance in the design;",
    "When designing butt welds, shear stresses perpendicular to the weld axis are considered.",
    "When designing butt welds (determination of allowable stresses), face and root bead reinforcements are considered as long as they are within the limits prescribed by a standard."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the externally applied stresses in welded joints, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["When designing butt welds, compressive or tensile stresses perpendicular to the weld axis are considered.",
    "The axial stress (in the longitudinal direction) of the weld is of most importance in the design;",
    "Shear stresses in the transverse direction of the fillet weld are important when designing steel structures;",
    "When designing butt welds (determination of allowable stresses), face and root bead reinforcements are considered as long as they are within the limits prescribed by a standard."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the equilibrium of a rigid body, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The equilibrium of two or more forces applied to a rigid body exists if a closed polygon of forces can be obtained;",
    "Statically determined systems are systems in which the support reactions are known;",
    "The number of unknowns associated with the reaction of a support can vary from one to three in three-dimensional structures;",
    "\"A rigid body will be in equilibrium if the external forces acting on it are reduced to a \"\"force - couple-moment\"\" system and both (the force and the couple-moment) are equal to zero.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the equilibrium of a rigid body, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The equilibrium of two or more forces applied to a rigid body exists if a closed polygon of forces can be obtained;",
    "The number of unknown reactions of a support is equal to the support degrees of freedom (DOF);",
    "The number of unknowns associated with the reaction of a support can vary from one to three in three-dimensional structures;",
    "In order for a system to be determinate the number of unknown forces and moments must be less than or equal to the number of independent equations of equilibrium available."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the equilibrium of a rigid body, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The equilibrium of two or more forces applied to a rigid body exists if a closed polygon of forces can be obtained;",
    "Statically determined systems are systems in which the support reactions are known;",
    "The number of unknowns associated with the reaction of a support can vary from one to three in three-dimensional structures;",
    "Statically indeterminate systems are systems in which the support reactions (forces and moments) cannot be determined with equilibrium equations alone."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the equilibrium of a rigid body, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The number of unknown reactions of a support is equal to the support degrees of freedom (DOF);",
    "Statically determined systems are systems in which the support reactions are known;",
    "The number of unknowns associated with the reaction of a support can vary from one to three in three-dimensional structures;",
    "The equilibrium of three or more forces applied to a rigid body exists if a closed polygon of forces can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Fatigue life will be significantly enhanced by:",
    answers: ["changing choice of material from mild steel to high strength steel;",
    "fulfilling a rounded concave fillet weld at the point where there is a change in diameter of a rotating shaft;",
    "adding secondary members, such as brackets, fitting etc, to reinforce the structure;",
    "using autogenous welding processes (without filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fatigue failure of a welded joint, which of the following is true?",
    answers: ["The peening technique, although costly, eliminates the risk of fatigue failure.",
    "The concave shape of the fillet weld surface does not enhance fatigue resistance.",
    "In general, low carbon steels are less sensitive to the influence of notches than high carbon steels.",
    "A high reinforcement of the welded joint does not influence fatigue failure as it is not characterized as a notch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fatigue failure of a welded joint, which of the following is true?",
    answers: ["The peening technique, although costly, eliminates the risk of fatigue failure.",
    "The concave shape of the fillet weld surface does not enhance fatigue resistance.",
    "Stress relieving a welded joint will enhance its fatigue resistance;",
    "A high reinforcement of the welded joint does not influence fatigue failure as it is not characterized as a notch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fatigue failure of a welded joint, which of the following is true?",
    answers: ["The peening technique, although costly, eliminates the risk of fatigue failure.",
    "The concave shape of the fillet weld surface does not enhance fatigue resistance.",
    "It is not advisable to use permanent backing strips for welded butt joints resistant to fatigue.",
    "A high reinforcement of the welded joint does not influence fatigue failure as it is not characterized as a notch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of residual stress appears in a weld metal after it has cooled?",
    answers: ["Compressive stress (longitudinal and transverse).",
    "Tensile stress (longitudinal and transverse).",
    "Longitudinal tensile and transverse compressive stresses.",
    "Shear stress."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the difference between the effect of ultraviolet radiation (UVR) and infrared radiation (IRR) on the human body?",
    answers: ["The UVR causes tanning while the IRR does not.",
    "The IRR causes tanning while the UVR does not.",
    "The short-wave IRR is less harmful to health than the long-wave IRR.",
    "The UVR provokes an immediate sensation of heat while the IRR does not."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the difference between the effect of ultraviolet radiation (UVR) and infrared radiation (IRR) on the human body?",
    answers: ["Both the UVR and the short-wave IRR can provoke an ocular damage.",
    "The IRR causes tanning while the UVR does not.",
    "The short-wave IRR is less harmful to health than the long-wave IRR.",
    "The UVR provokes an immediate sensation of heat while the IRR does not."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the difference between the effect of ultraviolet radiation (UVR) and infrared radiation (IRR) on the human body?",
    answers: ["The UVR is more prone to develop skin cancer.",
    "The IRR causes tanning while the UVR does not.",
    "The short-wave IRR is less harmful to health than the long-wave IRR.",
    "The UVR provokes an immediate sensation of heat while the IRR does not."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the deformation, it can be said:",
    answers: ["Elastic deformation of a rigid body occurs after exceeding the yield stress (yield limit).",
    "The plastic deformations are proportional to the applied stresses.",
    "Plastic deformations are fully reversible.",
    "Deformation occurs when a force is applied to a body, and it tends to change its shape and/or dimension."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Discontinuities in welding can have their origin in:",
    answers: ["Welding Techniques, Welder/Operator Skill, Standards used, among others;",
    "Joint design, Base material, Consumables used, among others;",
    "Welding equipment, Preparation and positioning of joints, NDT methods used, among others;",
    "Joint design, Welding Techniques, Destructive testing methods used, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Discontinuities in welding can have their origin in:",
    answers: ["Joint design, Base material, Standards used, among others;",
    "Welding equipment, Preparation and positioning of joints, Manufacturing Procedure, among others;",
    "Welding Techniques, Welder/Operator Skill, Standards used, among others;",
    "Joint design, Welding Techniques, Destructive testing methods used, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Discontinuities in welding can have their origin in:",
    answers: ["Joint design, Base material, Standards used, among others;",
    "Welding Techniques, Welder/Operator Skills, Base Metal and Filler Metal Mismatch, among others;",
    "Welding equipment, Preparation and positioning of joints, NDT methods used, among others;",
    "Joint design, Welding Techniques, Destructive testing methods used, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Magnetic Particle Testing (MP).",
    answers: ["It is not recommended to use the magnetization technique by using electrodes for inspection of finished machined parts.",
    "The shape or position of the discontinuity does not affect the detectability by Magnetic Particle Testing.",
    "The MP testing only detects a discontinuity (e.g., a crack) if it is parallel to the magnetic flux lines.",
    "The MP testing uses alternating current, as it is essential that the current changes its value to maintain a magnetic field."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Magnetic Particle Testing (MP).",
    answers: ["Parts inspected by the MP testing, which will be installed close to instruments that suffer interference from magnetic fields, must be demagnetized before use.",
    "The shape or position of the discontinuity does not affect the detectability by Magnetic Particle Testing.",
    "The MP testing only detects a discontinuity (e.g., a crack) if it is parallel to the magnetic flux lines.",
    "The MP testing uses alternating current, as it is essential that the current changes its value to maintain a magnetic field."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A WPS is only valid if there is a document that proves the quality of the joints welded by this specification containing the report of all relevant non-destructive and destructive tests. This document is:",
    answers: ["Welder Qualification Record (WQR);",
    "Welding Execution and Inspection Instruction (WEII);",
    "Complete Inspection Report (RIC);",
    "Welding Procedures Qualification Record (WPQR)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 14731 standard \"\"Welding Coordination - Tasks and Responsibilities\"\" defines:\"",
    answers: ["the need to certify welders and welding operators;",
    "the importance of Welding Engineer certification;",
    "the assignments and responsibilities of personnel involved in welding-related activities (e.g., planning, execution, supervision and inspection);",
    "four competency levels for welding coordination personnel (comprehensive, specific, standard and basic)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 14731 standard \"\"Welding Coordination - Tasks and Responsibilities\"\" defines:\"",
    answers: ["the need to certify welders and welding operators;",
    "the importance of Welding Engineer certification;",
    "that the company shall appoint at least one Welding Coordinator.",
    "four competency levels for welding coordination personnel (comprehensive, specific, standard and basic)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the ISO 5817 acceptability criteria, these discontinuities are not allowed at any of the quality levels (B, C and D):",
    answers: ["Cracks;",
    "Cracks and Lack of Fusion;",
    "Cracks, Lack of fusion and Lack of penetration;",
    "Cracks, lack of fusion, lack of penetration and clustered porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel based filler materials are widely used in repair jobs. This is because:",
    answers: ["They have good resistance to solidification cracking and hence are tolerant to some contaminants present on the surface of weld preparation;",
    "They are compatible with most metals and alloys, so are recommended when the base metal is not identified, which is typical for repair welds;",
    "In addition to having good ductility, they are widely used in several areas, so they are cheap and easy to find;",
    "They have good ductility and thus they can relax residual stresses by means of weld metal plastic deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel based filler materials are widely used in repair jobs. This is because:",
    answers: ["They have good resistance to solidification cracking and hence are tolerant to some contaminants present on the surface of weld preparation;",
    "They are compatible with most metals and alloys, so are recommended when the base metal is not identified, which is typical for repair welds;",
    "In addition to having good ductility, they are widely used in several areas, so they are cheap and easy to find;",
    "They do not form carbides and thus prevent diffusion of carbon from the HAZ to the deposited metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The main purpose of using reference blocks in UT is:",
    answers: ["to achieve the best possible sensitivity from the equipment;",
    "to adjust the sensitivity of the ultrasonic device, so that important discontinuities are detected and those that are not significant are ignored;",
    "a resolution check (equipment/transducer) for transverse (angular) wave head;",
    "verification of the linearity of the ultrasonic device under specific conditions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What would be better from the point of view of reducing welding costs (while maintaining the required mechanical characteristics of the joint)?",
    answers: ["To choose the groove geometry that needs less deposited metal.",
    "To give preference to oxyacetylene welding, as that process does not use electricity.",
    "To require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "To use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What would be better from the point of view of reducing welding costs (while maintaining the required mechanical characteristics of the joint)?",
    answers: ["To use single-sided welding whenever possible.",
    "To give preference to oxyacetylene welding, as that process does not use electricity.",
    "To require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "To use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What would be better from the point of view of reducing welding costs (while maintaining the required mechanical characteristics of the joint)?",
    answers: ["To use the X groove preparation instead of the V groove for thick plates.",
    "To give preference to oxyacetylene welding, as that process does not use electricity.",
    "To require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "To use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Is it a typical precaution to reduce the risk of cracking when welding rigid constructions?",
    answers: ["To apply post-weld vibration.",
    "To start welding from the region of lowest restriction in direction to those of higher restrictions.",
    "To use materials with a good plastic deformation capacity.",
    "To use rutile covered electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Is it a typical precaution to reduce the risk of cracking when welding rigid constructions?",
    answers: ["To apply post-weld vibration.",
    "To start welding from the region of lowest restriction in direction to those of higher restrictions.",
    "To use basic covered electrodes with high toughness.",
    "To use rutile covered electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "It is a requirement of ISO 9001:2015, prescribing that the organisation shall be able to identify and trace their products and services."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "\"According to ISO 3834-2 \"\"Identification and traceability shall be maintained throughout the manufacturing process, if required\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "It is used to identify parts throughout the production process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "It is used to retrieve the manufacturing history of a product."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is the monitoring of the entire course of a raw material, from its origin to its use in the final product."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding traceability, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The need for traceability arose due to complaints from the most demanding customers;",
    "Traceability is necessary primarily to minimize the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Traceability is firstly necessary so that the contractor cannot escape civil liability for the service;",
    "It allows managers to identify the main production bottlenecks, in the supply of inputs and in logistics, making operations more efficient."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses and Distortions:",
    answers: ["Residual stresses equilibrated within the part boundaries are called macrostresses;",
    "Residual stresses equilibrated within the part boundaries are called microstresses;",
    "Stresses equilibrated within grain boundaries or between some neighboring grains are called macrostresses;",
    "Residual micro- and macrostresses do not add up to applied external stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses and Distortions:",
    answers: ["Stresses equilibrated within grain boundaries or between some neighboring grains are called microstresses;",
    "Residual stresses equilibrated within the part boundaries are called microstresses;",
    "Stresses equilibrated within grain boundaries or between some neighboring grains are called macrostresses;",
    "Residual micro- and macrostresses do not add up to applied external stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses and Distortions:",
    answers: ["Residual stresses that occur over various atomic distances within a grain and are balanced over a small part of the grain are called microlocalized stresses;",
    "Residual stresses equilibrated within the part boundaries are called microstresses;",
    "Stresses equilibrated within grain boundaries or between some neighboring grains are called macrostresses;",
    "Residual micro- and macrostresses do not add up to applied external stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding Residual Stresses and Distortions:",
    answers: ["Residual stresses can cause unexpected and premature failure of a component when, under external loading, they can add to the applied stresses;",
    "Residual stresses equilibrated within the part boundaries are called microstresses;",
    "Stresses equilibrated within grain boundaries or between some neighboring grains are called macrostresses;",
    "Residual micro- and macrostresses do not add up to applied external stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the generation of thermal stresses in welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The higher the welding energy, the lower the thermal stresses, due to the stress relief caused by slow cooling;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld during heating and cooling are tensile;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld and in the HAZ after cooling are tensile, whereas the base metal from the side is under the compressive forces action;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the generation of thermal stresses in welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The higher the welding energy, the lower the thermal stresses, due to the stress relief caused by slow cooling;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld during heating and cooling are tensile;",
    "During heating, the weld region tends to expand, but self-restriction (from the plate itself) or an external restriction prevent from it, thus generating thermal stresses;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the generation of thermal stresses in welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The higher the welding energy, the lower the thermal stresses, due to the stress relief caused by slow cooling;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld during heating and cooling are tensile;",
    "The weld pool metal does not exert compressive or tensile stresses on the base metal;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the generation of thermal stresses in welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The higher the welding energy, the lower the thermal stresses, due to the stress relief caused by slow cooling;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld during heating and cooling are tensile;",
    "During the cooling of the weld metal, tensile stresses are generated, as its yield strength increases with the reduction of temperature;",
    "The longitudinal stresses generated in the weld after cooling are tensile, but the transverse stresses are compressive."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}]
    ;